<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.piie.com/">
  <channel>
    <title>Peterson Institute Update</title>
    <link>https://www.piie.com/</link>
    <description/>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.piie.com/rss/update.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

    <item>
  <title>How to Win a Trade War</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/bookstore/2025/how-win-trade-war</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2026 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Soumaya Keynes, Chad P. Bown</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/bookstore/2025/how-win-trade-war</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Bridges and borders: Economic policy across North America</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/events/2025/bridges-and-borders-economic-policy-across-north-america</link>
  <description>This conference organized by PIIE and the Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas examines key policy and economic challenges shaping the future of North American integration, with a focus on labor mobility, remittance flows, and cross-border trade. As the region navigates shifting immigration dynamics and prepares for a pivotal review of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement in 2026, conference sessions explore how policy decisions affect economic resilience, productivity, and regional cooperation. Experts assess the implications for workers, firms, and communities and consider strategies for…</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Michael A. Clemens, Monica de Bolle</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/events/2025/bridges-and-borders-economic-policy-across-north-america</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Central bank independence in practice</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/events/2025/central-bank-independence-practice</link>
  <description>The Peterson Institute for International Economics holds a high-level conference to analyze the serious issues concerning central bank independence in practice. Featuring an opening discussion with John H. Cochrane (Hoover Institution) and Lawrence H. Summers (Harvard University), and leading voices from academia, policy, and finance, the conference addresses:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Does the evidence for the benefits of central bank independence hold up on net and through recent data?&lt;br&gt;
What is and should be the constitutional and legal extent of the independence of Federal Reserve?&lt;br&gt;
Does the current system of…</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 08:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator/>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/events/2025/central-bank-independence-practice</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>The London Consensus: Economic Principles for the 21st Century</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/events/2025/london-consensus-economic-principles-21st-century</link>
  <description>Forty years ago, the Washington Consensus emerged. John Williamson of PIIE laid out a series of dos and don’ts for policymakers in Latin America that found acceptance around the world. Despite its influence, the Washington Consensus has since been widely criticized and often mischaracterized in terms of its approach and scope. The challenge remains to identify a set of new ideas—and policies—that can guide us through the challenges humanity faces today.&amp;nbsp;Convened at the London School of Economics and Political Science (LSE), The London Consensus: Economic Principles for the 21st Century,…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>C. Fred Bergsten, Cecilia Malmström, Tim Besley, Şebnem Kalemli-Özcan, Andrés Velasco</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/events/2025/london-consensus-economic-principles-21st-century</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Europe in a changing international monetary system</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/events/2025/europe-changing-international-monetary-system</link>
  <description>Europe is navigating profound shifts in the global monetary system and financial flows, presenting both risks and opportunities for the future of the euro. This high-level discussion examines how Europe can strengthen its fiscal, economic, and monetary architecture to address these challenges and capitalize on emerging opportunities.&lt;br&gt;
Bringing together central bank governors alongside leading voices from policy and research, this event explores Europe's fiscal capacity, resilience, and medium-term economic outlook, with particular attention to the evolving role of eurobonds and Europe's…</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Jacob Funk Kirkegaard, Klaas Knot, Signe Krogstrup, Olli Rehn, Ángel Ubide</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/events/2025/europe-changing-international-monetary-system</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Canada's economic outlook and global trade: A conversation with Governor Tiff Macklem</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/events/2025/canadas-economic-outlook-and-global-trade-conversation-governor-tiff-macklem</link>
  <description>The Peterson Institute for International Economics welcomes Tiff Macklem, governor of the Bank of Canada, for a keynote address on Canada’s monetary policy and economic outlook. Macklem shares perspectives on global trade and financial stability, building on recent insights and research from the Bank of Canada’s leadership.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Following his remarks, Macklem joins Adam S. Posen, PIIE president, for a moderated conversation and take questions from the audience.&lt;br&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Tiff Macklem, Adam S. Posen</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/events/2025/canadas-economic-outlook-and-global-trade-conversation-governor-tiff-macklem</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>The changing dollar regime: An update</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/events/2025/changing-dollar-regime-update</link>
  <description>This event revisits and expands on themes from PIIE’s spring discussion, “Does changing the trade regime change the dollar regime? To Mar-a-Lago and beyond.” Against the backdrop of shifting trade policies, financial flows, and geopolitical realignments, the panel explores if and how the dollar’s role in the global economy may evolve.&lt;br&gt;
Maurice Obstfeld shares his latest insights on the international role of the dollar in light of recent policy changes. Moritz Schularick analyzes the evolving and increasing significance of the euro within the global monetary system. Joseph E. Gagnon provides…</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Adam S. Posen, Joseph E. Gagnon, Maurice Obstfeld, Moritz Schularick</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/events/2025/changing-dollar-regime-update</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>A new trading landscape: How is the world adjusting?</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/events/2025/new-trading-landscape-how-world-adjusting</link>
  <description>Since the so-called Liberation Day in April, several countries have made “deals” with the Trump administration. Others have not but are trying to navigate in a new landscape of tariffs and trade distortion. Should developing countries consider new trade agreements with other partners, such as the newly concluded free trade agreement between the European Union and Indonesia? Are there any prospects of reform for the World Trade Organization? What consequences can we see for the future of digital trade, where the origins cannot be as easily tracked as for goods?&lt;br&gt;
HOST&lt;br&gt;
Cecilia…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Cecilia Malmström, Mari Elka Pangestu, Hector Torres</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/events/2025/new-trading-landscape-how-world-adjusting</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>Maurice Obstfeld on trade and the international financial system</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/events/2025/maurice-obstfeld-trade-and-international-financial-system</link>
  <description>Maurice Obstfeld, PIIE C. Fred Bergsten senior fellow, joins Anjali V. Bhatt, PIIE communications manager and research fellow, for a live, virtual conversation about tariffs in the US as fiscal policy , the future of the US-centric, dollar-based international monetary and financial system, and more.&lt;br&gt;
PIIE Insider LIVE brings the exclusive content in our flagship newsletter, PIIE Insider, to your screen (and headphones). Bhatt chats with PIIE experts to explain their research and give insights you won’t get anywhere else, learn what they think of the latest news, and what it means for the…</description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Anjali V. Bhatt, Maurice Obstfeld</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/events/2025/maurice-obstfeld-trade-and-international-financial-system</guid>
    </item>
<item>
  <title>A Sixth Of Humanity: Independent India's Development Odyssey</title>
  <link>https://www.piie.com/bookstore/2025/sixth-humanity-independent-indias-development-odyssey</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Devesh Kapur, Arvind Subramanian</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.piie.com/bookstore/2025/sixth-humanity-independent-indias-development-odyssey</guid>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
