﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>
<atom:link href="https://www.wto.org/library/rss/latest_news_e.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<title>World Trade Organization — Latest news</title> 
<link>http://www.wto.org</link> 
<description>World Trade Organization — Latest news</description> 
<image>
	<url>http://www.wto.org/images/podcast_logo_144x144pxls.gif</url>
	<title>World Trade Organization — Latest news</title>
	<link>http://www.wto.org</link>
</image>
<ttl>15</ttl>
<itunes:author>WTO</itunes:author>
<itunes:owner>
	<itunes:name>WTO</itunes:name>
	<itunes:email>webmaster@wto.org</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<itunes:image href="http://www.wto.org/images/podcast_logo_300x300pxls.gif"/>
<itunes:category text="Business" />
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:keywords>World Trade Organization, WTO</itunes:keywords>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:57:24 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:57:24 GMT</lastBuildDate> 
<language>en-us</language> 
<copyright>Copyright 2025 WTO</copyright>

<item>
 <title>DG Okonjo-Iweala: WTO “has important tools worth preserving”</title>
 <description><![CDATA[At a meeting of the WTO’s General Council on 6-7 October, Director-General Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala once again underlined the need for fundamental reform of the organization but also highlighted that the WTO “provides important tools that are worth preserving.” The facilitator for the ongoing reform talks delivered his latest update report on the exchanges. WTO members also addressed current developments in global trade, ongoing work and initiatives, and other issues during their two-day meeting, while Saudi Arabia indicated its readiness to host the organization’s 15th Ministerial Conference.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/gc_07oct25_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/gc_07oct25_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>AI goods and frontloading lift world trade in 2025 but outlook dims for 2026</title>
 <description><![CDATA[Global merchandise trade outpaced expectations in the first half of 2025, driven by increased spending on AI-related products, a surge in North American imports ahead of tariff hikes, and strong trade among the rest of the world. In response, WTO economists raised the 2025 merchandise trade growth forecast to 2.4% (up from 0.9% in August). However, the 2026 projection has been lowered to 0.5% (from 1.8%). Global services exports growth is expected to slow from 6.8% in 2024 to 4.6% in 2025 and 4.4% in 2026.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/stat_07oct25_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/stat_07oct25_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO members discuss professional qualification recognition and other services trade issues</title>
 <description><![CDATA[The WTO Council for Trade in Services met on 2 and 3 October to discuss how to facilitate the recognition of professional qualifications to promote services trade and development. Members also considered the way forward for a proposal in support of least-developed countries and discussed various services trade concerns. ]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/serv_03oct25_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/serv_03oct25_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>MSME Working Group reviews new trade initiatives, highlights exemplary businesses </title>
 <description><![CDATA[The Informal Working Group on Micro, Small and Medium-sized Enterprises (MSMEs) on 3 October reviewed recent initiatives in international fora aimed at empowering small businesses through trade and highlighted preparations for the 14th Ministerial Conference (MC14). Several small businesses were showcased and participants shared experiences on helping companies transition from the informal economy. ]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/msmes_03oct25_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/msmes_03oct25_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO members share tools and insights to advance fossil fuel subsidy reform</title>
 <description><![CDATA[WTO members participating in the Fossil Fuel Subsidy Reform (FFSR) initiative met on 2 October to share experiences on fiscal tools and programmes for subsidy reform, as well as on fossil fuel subsidies provided to emissions-intensive sectors. They also reviewed work on rolling back crisis-related energy support measures and enhancing transparency of fossil fuel subsidies.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/ffsr_02oct25_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/ffsr_02oct25_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Committee reviews work on transparency, discusses AI, semiconductors, metrology in trade </title>
 <description><![CDATA[At a meeting on 2 October, the WTO Committee on Technical Barriers to Trade (TBT) advanced preparations for thematic discussions on critical and emerging technologies, good regulatory practices and metrology in trade to be held in November. WTO members also considered further refining their notification processes and the way their TBT measures are tracked in the ePing platform.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/tbt_03oct25_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/tbt_03oct25_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO Fish Fund fully operational, first Call for Proposals closes next week</title>
 <description><![CDATA[Following the entry into force of the WTO Agreement on Fisheries Subsidies on 15 September, the WTO Fish Fund is fully operational and ready to support WTO members in implementing the Agreement. Developing and least-developed members that have submitted their instrument of acceptance for the Agreement can submit proposals for project grants and project preparation grants until 9 October.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/ffm_02oct25_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/ffm_02oct25_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO panel issues report regarding EU duties on Indonesian steel products</title>
 <description><![CDATA[On 2 October, the WTO circulated the panel report in the case brought by Indonesia in “European Union  —  Countervailing and Anti-Dumping Duties on Stainless Steel Cold-Rolled Flat Products from Indonesia“(DS616).]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/616r_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/616r_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>DG Okonjo-Iweala welcomes calls of support for WTO, urges meaningful MC14 outcomes</title>
 <description><![CDATA[Director-General Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala welcomed recent calls of support for the WTO and the multilateral trading system from world leaders and urged members to show the political will and flexibility to achieve meaningful outcomes at the WTO’s 14th Ministerial Conference (MC14) in March 2026. The Director-General delivered her remarks at a 30 September meeting of the WTO’s Trade Negotiations Committee (TNC) which she chairs.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/tnc_30sep25_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news25_e/tnc_30sep25_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Bahrain  contributes USD 200,000 to WTO–ITC Fund  to support women exporters</title>
 <description><![CDATA[More women entrepreneurs will be able to expand their digital and export skills following a new contribution from the Kingdom of Bahrain to a global fund set up to help expand opportunities for women-led businesses in international trade.  The World Trade Organization (WTO) Secretariat and the International Trade Centre (ITC) today (29 September) signed a memorandum of understanding (MoU) with the Kingdom of Bahrain at WTO headquarters in Geneva , confirming a contribution of USD 200,000 to the Women Exporters in the Digital Economy (WEIDE) Fund. ]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/pres25_e/pr985_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/pres25_e/pr985_e.htm</guid>
</item>

</channel> 
</rss>